<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scripting Portfolio on Jason C. Mitchell</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scripting Portfolio on Jason C. Mitchell</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alma License Creation Script</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/license_creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/license_creation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Managing electronic resource licenses efficiently is a crucial part of library acquisitions workflows. To streamline this process, I developed a set of Python scripts that automate the creation and submission of license records in Alma. These scripts take structured data from an Excel file, convert it into XML, split it into individual records, and push them to Alma’s API.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post breaks down how the three scripts—license_creation.py, license_split.py, and license_push.py—work together to automate license record management.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OCLC Work ID Retrieval Script</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/work_id/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/work_id/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Libraries rely on accurate metadata to manage collections, align bookstore adoption lists with their catalogs, and reconcile electronic and physical holdings. However, matching titles across various editions and formats remains a persistent challenge for technical services staff. The OCLC Work ID serves as a crucial data point for disambiguating records, grouping related editions, and enhancing bibliographic consistency.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To address this challenge, I developed a script that automates the retrieval of Work IDs using OCLC’s WorldCat Search API v.2. This tool enables library staff to efficiently identify and compare records based on ISBNs, improving metadata management and acquisitions workflows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GOBI Duplicate Purchase Checker</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/duplicate_checker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/duplicate_checker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;GOBI Duplicate Purchase Checker&lt;/strong&gt; is a helpful tool for libraries using the GOBI platform and Alma to streamline acquisitions workflows. By automating the process of checking for duplicate holdings in Alma’s Institution Zone (IZ) via the SRU (Search/Retrieve via URL) protocol, it reduces manual effort and supports more efficient collection management.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The original version of this tool, developed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MrJeremyHobbs/GobiChecker&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;Jeremy Hobbs&lt;/a&gt;, was designed for institutions using both an Institution Zone (IZ) and a Network Zone (NZ). However, since Loyola Marymount University operates without a Network Zone, I adapted the script to better fit our specific needs. These changes aim to expand the tool’s usefulness for libraries like ours and refine its functionality to address nuances in our acquisitions workflows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
