<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Jason C. Mitchell</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Jason C. Mitchell</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, and welcome to my articles! I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to have you here. My name is Jason, and I am the library assistant for electronic resources at Loyola Marymount University in Los Angeles, California. I am incredibly passionate about the intersection of technology and library science.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my day-to-day work, I handle a range of tasks, from updating the LibGuides A-Z list and troubleshooting electronic resource access issues to developing custom scripts for metadata harvest. I frequently interface with library stakeholders and vendors to resolve issues, develop systems-based approaches to manage metadata, and create custom scripts for ensuring metadata compliance. Additionally, I’ve been involved in creating procedural documentation, analyzing workflows, and spearheading assessments to improve acquisition workflows, especially after our Integrated Library System (ILS) migration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choosing Python as My Primary Scriptng Language</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/choosing_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/choosing_python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As someone who spends a significant amount of time managing metadata, troubleshooting electronic resource access, and creating custom tools for library workflows, scripting has become an indispensable part of my professional toolkit. Early in my journey, I made the decision to adopt Python as my primary scripting language, a choice that has shaped how I approach problem-solving and automation in technical services. But like any decision, it’s worth revisiting periodically to ensure it still aligns with my needs and goals. Lately, I’ve been broadening my horizons, exploring other scripting languages, particularly Bash, and reflecting on what Python offers compared to other tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
